<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kelly Ripple</title>
    <link>https://username.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kelly Ripple</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://username.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>BTI Goes International</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/bti-goes-international/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/bti-goes-international/</guid>
      <description>I started with BTI in January. On June 1st, a mere five months later, I found myself on a fully funded international plane ride to the Dominican Republic, alongside an assorted group of BTI teammates and their spouses. Why in the world did BTI send us to the DR, you may ask? We returned to the states a few days ago, and I think I may have a few of the answers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Bootcamp: The Final Weeks</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/dbc-the-final-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/dbc-the-final-weeks/</guid>
      <description>Wednesday (9/16/15) 11:00 AM - The End is Near We&amp;rsquo;re almost at the end! The tension and anticipation is building .. what will our final projects be!? Will they be good? Will we impress?
This week is much better than last. My day off helped. I would go so far as to say my day off was mandatory for me to be functional now. The stressful commute is wearying and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the day where I can have more power in my choice of environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Bootcamp: Phase 3, Week 1</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/dbc-week-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/dbc-week-7/</guid>
      <description>Week 7 - Hello, Burnout This week we played with RSpec testing and Rails. Rails comes with all kinds of shortcut goodies that seem really cool until you have to debug them. It&amp;rsquo;s much more confusing to debug a helper function that hides what it&amp;rsquo;s doing than to debug something you wrote yourself. Rails is difficult to learn, is what I&amp;rsquo;m saying.
Our weekend project was to make a clone of StackOverflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Bootcamp: Phase 2, Week 3</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/dbc-week-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/dbc-week-6/</guid>
      <description>Monday, 6:17 PM - All Time Low Today was the absolute worst.
This weekend, we had our second group project. It actually went really well. We were effective as a team and completed some cool features beyond the basic requirements. I, unfortunately, missed the Monday morning demo. I was accidentally late in the morning, in excess of one hour. I put my guides in the uncomfortable position of having to inform me that if it happens again I will acrue a &amp;ldquo;breach of integrity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Bootcamp: Phase 2, Week 2</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/dbc-week-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/dbc-week-5/</guid>
      <description>Last week was the most difficult week DBC has to offer, or so they say. I can attest that it was massively challenging, and this week was no cakewalk either.
Monday - All I need is a break We had our weekend code reviewed today. The session was positive and encouraging. We got some valuable firsthand experience on Big Design Upfront (BDUF) vs. Agile. The short version is that BDUF is only viable if you have large amounts of time and money to spend ( as is often not the case ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Bootcamp: Phase 2, Week 1</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/dbc-week-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/dbc-week-4/</guid>
      <description>Monday, 6:44 PM - New Beginings Today was spectacular for a number of reasons. Let me enumerate them for you:
 New people! Having new faces in the space was exciting and refreshing. The material. I&amp;rsquo;m pleasantly surprised to learn that I absolutely love what we&amp;rsquo;re working on. That being said, my brain feels as though it&amp;rsquo;s been put through the ringer. We&amp;rsquo;re learning A LOT of new things, all at once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Bootcamp: Phase 1, Week 3</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/dbc-week-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/dbc-week-3/</guid>
      <description>Monday, 10:00 PM - Monday Funday I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m finally setting into a rhythm. Today we learned SQL - a database query language. It&amp;rsquo;s got some quirks, but it&amp;rsquo;s fairly straightforward for the most part and we got plenty of repitition in today. I feel as though I have a sense for it now, even if I don&amp;rsquo;t always understand why a complicated query works.
We had a party in the evening today and last week we had an Alumni AMA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Bootcamp: Phase 1, Week 2</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/dbc-week-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/dbc-week-2/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve survived another week. It feels as though I&amp;rsquo;ve been here 8 months, not two weeks. DBC time distortion is real.
Monday, 6:21 PM - Bring it on I AM DONE!!!!!!!! This is a momentous occasion. Today is the first day I completed all of the day&amp;rsquo;s challenges, and so close to 6 PM (end of day). Yay.
My experience of today:
Super, super tired this morning. I had 2 cups of coffee, and it&amp;rsquo;s got me a bit edgy and headache-y.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Bootcamp: Phase 1, Week 1</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/dbc-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/dbc-week-1/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure what my blog format will be at this point. I know that I want to capture what the DBC experience is for me, and I want to blog about it. Below are my daily reflections for my first week.
July 27, 9:03 PM - What have I gotten myself into? I kid! Today was great. We met all the staff, got to meet everyone face-to-face. I&amp;rsquo;m less intimidated by the process now that I&amp;rsquo;ve met the people behind it (probabaly becuase they work to mitigate the intimidation factor - at least I think that&amp;rsquo;s what they&amp;rsquo;re doing).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/questions/</guid>
      <description>This week&amp;rsquo;s cultural reflection piece is about asking good questions. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I know about questions:
 Asking for help is about connection. It makes the asker vulnerable to their audience. The asker needs to trust that the askee (or group at large) will want to help them. Without trust and the willingness to be vulnerable, questions will not be as effective. Some of the most important questions are the ones we ask ourselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conflicts &#43; Emotional Awareness</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/conflicts-and-emotional-awareness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/conflicts-and-emotional-awareness/</guid>
      <description>My natural inclination is to avoid conflict. For my own personal development, I need to learn how to speak up when something bothers me. What I do instead (all too often) is nothing externally, but internally store the anger, sadness, or hurt feelings. This isn&amp;rsquo;t healthy, fosters poor communication, and has probably stunted my efforts in learning to be tactful/assertive in my speaking.
Describe a time when &amp;hellip; Discuss a time you had a conflict.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Internet Works</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/how-the-internet-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/how-the-internet-works/</guid>
      <description>As an aspiring web developer, I acknowledge that the internet will play a large role in my future. But, what is the internet, and how does it work? I like the explanation in this youtube video. Let me summarize.
The internet is a wire in the ground. The first time people had the bright idea to send messages quickly through wires, they laid lots of copper in the ground. We called the invention the telephone, perhaps you have heard of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby vs. Javascript</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/ruby-vs-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/ruby-vs-javascript/</guid>
      <description>I used JavaScript for the first time this week (woo!). This post will be about JavaScript, the programming language, and how it differs in syntax and useability from a few other languages.
I first learned how to program in high school. The year was 2007 and the language was Visual Basic. To me, it was a simple, easy to use, easy to learn language. In college I learned C, along with the basics of computer organization and machine languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fighting the Good Fight</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/fighting-the-good-fight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/fighting-the-good-fight/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I reflected on Stereotype Threat and the DevBootcamp educational experience. This week, I&amp;rsquo;ll take it a step further and discuss how to fight stereotype threat and other nasties like the imposter syndrome.
A little bit about me - I pursued an engineering degree from a well respected educational institution. I had a number of classes where I was the only female in the room. None of my engineering classes even approached a 50&amp;frasl;50 M-to-F ratio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby Building Blocks</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/ruby-building-blocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/ruby-building-blocks/</guid>
      <description>I feel like a toddler. My brain hurts and nothing makes sense. The internet insists on explaining things to me like I already know things. Dear Internet, I most certainly do not. I have included here the stuff that did make sense. May these humble building blocks aid you in your own pursuit of understanding.
Modules vs. Classes From my blog post on the map method, a module is a way of grouping together methods, classes, and constants - a collection of reuseable code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stereotype Threat</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/stereotype-threat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/stereotype-threat/</guid>
      <description>Preface One reason I love Dev Bootcamp is it&amp;rsquo;s holistic education of the whole individual. They&amp;rsquo;ve taken on the task of educating people about the world they will need to be able to work in. They don&amp;rsquo;t produce programmers that are only suited to programming in a vacuum, but developers capable of interacting with other developers and dealing wih the cultural climate of the day. They&amp;rsquo;re comitted to teaching skills beyond the technical - they teach social awareness skills - and in so doing, they treat the student as an inlelligent, aware person, not a tool suited to performing a specific kind of task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lets Get Classy</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/lets-get-classy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/lets-get-classy/</guid>
      <description>I learned how to use a new Ruby &amp;lsquo;thing&amp;rsquo; this week: Classes. To be completely honest with you, I don&amp;rsquo;t completely understand what&amp;rsquo;s going on with the Ruby &amp;lsquo;class&amp;rsquo; object, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it, and I think I can do a reasonably competent job explaining the basics. Also this week, I learned some new tricks for arrays and hashes. Check them out at the end of my post from a few weeks ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedback &amp; Pairing</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/feedback-and-pairing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/feedback-and-pairing/</guid>
      <description>Below are my responses to some questions about the experiences of giving/recieving feedback and peer programming (pairing).
Pairing What was it like to pair with others to solve challenges?
 Sometimes I felt held back, other times I felt pulled forward. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure yet which factors impact whether it will be the first case or the second. I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced both with the same person, so I know the success of the pairing is not wholly dependent on the individuals involved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Method: Map</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/method-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/method-map/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m quite new to the realm of Ruby. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, I&amp;rsquo;m a hughe fan. There are just a few things (many, many things) that I don&amp;rsquo;t quite understand yet. I&amp;rsquo;m going to throw some concept descriptions down below, but just so you know where I&amp;rsquo;m going with this - this post is about the Ruby &amp;lsquo;map&amp;rsquo; method. It&amp;rsquo;s a super-simple, super-useful method. See below for descriptions and examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sitting is Bad for You</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/sitting-is-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/sitting-is-bad/</guid>
      <description>This week&amp;rsquo;s cultural blogging assignment was to reflect on one of the various issues facing the tech industry. Suggestions included &amp;lsquo;Diversity in Tech&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Designing for Accessibility&amp;rsquo;, and &amp;lsquo;Online Security&amp;rsquo;. I decided to approach the question from a broader perspective. I think that one of the most prevalent issues in the tech industry today (and in many other industries, besides) is cultivating optimal physical health while suceeding at work in a traditional desk job environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking About Thinking</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/thinking-about-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/thinking-about-thinking/</guid>
      <description>The relationship people have with information differs for each individual. This is an important concept for two reasons: personal growth and communication skills. A man named Anthony Gregorc did some research on Mind Styles. I&amp;rsquo;ll be discussing what I learned from identifying my own mind style in the hope that reading will help you in your own introspective journey.
First things first, what are Mind Styles? Mind Styles categorize the way a person sequences and relates to information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hash-tastic</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/hashtastic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/hashtastic/</guid>
      <description>This week I learned about the glorious data storage object that is the Hash. The following will be some fun information on how to differentiate, define, and reference arrays and hashes. Arrays and hashes are both constucts used for data storage. Their construction and syntax are different, so depending on what you&amp;rsquo;re trying to do, one will likely be better than the other for specific applications.
Define Array Ordered, iteger-indexed collections of any object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Madness</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/css-madness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/css-madness/</guid>
      <description>I spent the past week learning HTML and CSS, having zero prior experience with either. With the right guidance, it&amp;rsquo;s surprisingly doable. No learning experience is complete without some moments of struggle, and I had plenty. Hopefully you will be able to benefit from my pain. The two worst positioning nightmares I came accross were position:relative/absolute/fixed and display:inline/block/inline-block. I&amp;rsquo;ll run through the definitions of each, and include my advice on using the things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git vs. Github</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/git-vs-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/git-vs-github/</guid>
      <description>Hello reader! This is my first blog post EVER, so please be generous with your feedback, should you have any.
Let me start off by saying that Git and Github are completely different things, I know, I was shocked too. People throw around the word &amp;lsquo;Github&amp;rsquo; enough that it starts to seem more magical than it really is. Github.com is just a website. It functions a lot like Dropbox - a place to remotely store things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoga &amp; Devbootcamp</title>
      <link>https://username.github.io/post/yoga-and-devbootcamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kelly.ripple@bti360.com (Kelly Ripple)</author>
      <guid>https://username.github.io/post/yoga-and-devbootcamp/</guid>
      <description>I never thought this day would come - me with a blog. I somehow doubt that blogging and tweeting will be the only new behaviors I will inherit from this educational adventure called Devbootcamp. This post marks the completion point of week one. The following is my response to a discussion on DBC culture.
I was first introduced to the DBC philosophy in a yoga studio. I&amp;rsquo;ve been an avid hot yoga practitioner for the past few years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>